Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we're going to have a fun, funny lesson.
今天我们要上一节有趣又好笑的课。
That's right.
没错。
So I think this lesson's going to be a little bit different than most of our lessons, right?
所以我觉得这节课会和我们大多数课有点不一样，对吧？
Right.
对。
Today we're going to be looking at jokes, which is a very important part of English
今天我们要看笑话，这是英语口语文化中非常重要的一部分。
speaking culture.
口语文化。
Yeah.
是的。
So we're actually, we're going to teach you a few pretty hilarious jokes, but we're also
所以我们实际上要教你们几个非常好笑的笑话，同时也会教你们一些与笑话、搞笑事物相关的语言。
going to teach you some language related to jokes, funny things, and that sort of stuff.
以及这类东西。
All right.
好的。
So in order for us to understand a little bit better the jokes that we're going to be
为了让我们更好地理解要看的笑话，不如先来看看词汇预览。
looking at, why don't we take a look at vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
Two of these words you'll hear in the dialogue, but one you won't, but you still need to know
这些词中有两个你会在对话里听到，但有一个不会，不过你仍然需要知道这个词，这样才能理解笑话。
this word so you can understand the jokes.
好的。
All right.
So the word that we're talking about is not really a word.
我们要说的这个词其实不算一个词。
It's a sound.
它是一个声音。
Yeah.
是的。
It's a sound.
它是一个声音。
Moo.
哞。
So moo is the sound that cows make.
所以“哞”是牛发出的声音。
That's right.
没错。
M-O-O.
M-O-O。
Right.
对。
They go moo.
它们发出“哞”的声音。
Very nice, Marco.
学得很像，Marco。
I could do a good cow.
我能学牛学得很好。
Yep.
嗯。
All right.
好的。
So we all know now that that's what cows say.
所以我们现在都知道牛是怎么叫的了。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So it's going to be important for the joke.
所以这对理解笑话很重要。
You'll see why.
你一会儿就会明白为什么。
Okay.
好的。
Now another word that you need to understand is a dam.
现在你需要理解的另一个词是“dam”（水坝）。
So a dam.
所以是“dam”。
A dam.
“dam”。
A dam is like a big wall, right?
“dam”就像一堵大墙，对吧？
Well, it's a wall in water that stops the river from flowing.
嗯，它是水中的一堵墙，用来阻止河流流动。
Okay.
好的。
So usually you build dams in rivers and then the water can pass or not.
所以通常你在河里建水坝，然后水可以流过或不能流过。
Yeah.
是的。
It's something that you use to generate electricity, right?
它是用来发电的东西，对吧？
Very good.
非常好。
But there's another word that sounds exactly the same way, but it's just spelled a little
但还有一个词发音完全一样，只是拼写略有不同。
differently.
没错。
That's right.
And we might hear someone say, oh, damn.
我们可能会听到有人说“oh, damn”（哦，该死）。
And that's an interjection, which basically means...
那是一个感叹词，基本上意思是……
Oh no.
哦不。
Right.
对。
That's terrible.
太糟糕了。
Yeah.
是的。
Damn.
该死。
We're late for the movies.
我们看电影迟到了。
Damn.
该死。
We're late for the movie.
我们看电影迟到了。
Okay.
好的。
So it's an interesting interjection and we'll also see it in one of our jokes.
所以这是一个有趣的感叹词，我们也会在其中一个笑话里看到它。
And now let's move on to our last word.
现在让我们继续看最后一个词。
Nostrils.
鼻孔。
Okay.
好的。
Nostrils.
鼻孔。
So a nostril or your nostrils.
所以一个鼻孔或你的鼻孔。
The two holes in your nose.
你鼻子上的两个洞。
Right.
对。
You breathe through your nostrils.
你通过鼻孔呼吸。
All right.
好的。
So now that we've taken a look at these three words, why don't we listen to our comedian
现在我们已经看了这三个词，不如先听一遍我们的喜剧演员表演，然后我们再回来多聊一聊。
for the first time and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more.
大家好，欢迎来到开放麦之夜。
Hello everyone and welcome to Open Mic Night.
You're in for a real treat as we've got a lot of great comics here with us tonight.
你们今晚有福了，因为我们这里来了很多很棒的喜剧演员。
First up, we have a very funny man coming straight from the state of Montana, Robert
首先上场的是来自蒙大拿州的一位非常有趣的人，Robert Hicks。
Hicks.
Robert Hicks。
Thank you everyone.
谢谢大家。
Well, what a lovely crowd.
哇，多可爱的观众啊。
You know, there's nothing I love better than stand up comedy.
你们知道吗，我最喜欢的就是单口喜剧了。
You know, I've been working on my routine for months now and I've got some real zingers
你们知道，我已经为我的段子练习了好几个月，今晚我给你们准备了一些真正的爆笑梗。
for you tonight.
今晚我给你们准备了一些真正的爆笑梗。
Let's start out with some short jokes.
我们先从几个短笑话开始吧。
How about that?
怎么样？
Where do you find a one-legged dog?
你在哪里能找到一条腿的狗？
Where you left it?
在你把它留下的地方。
Get it?
懂了吗？
Anyways, what do you call a sheep with no legs?
不管怎样，你管没有腿的羊叫什么？
A cloud.
一朵云。
Tough crowd.
观众真难搞。
All right.
好吧。
Now, you're going to love this joke.
现在，你们会喜欢这个笑话的。
It's hilarious.
它超好笑。
What do cows do for entertainment?
牛为了娱乐会做什么？
They rent movies.
它们租电影看。
Movies.
电影。
Okay, okay, okay.
好吧，好吧，好吧。
We've got a few hecklers in the audience, but this one is good.
观众里有几个捣乱的人，但这个笑话很好。
What does a fish say when it runs into a wall?
鱼撞到墙时会说什么？
Damn!
该死！
Get out of here.
滚出去。
Okay, okay, okay.
好吧，好吧，好吧。
Last one.
最后一个。
Why do gorillas have big nostrils?
为什么大猩猩有大鼻孔？
Because they got big fingers.
因为它们有大手指。
Thanks, everyone.
谢谢大家。
That was my time.
我的时间到了。
Okay, so some pretty hilarious jokes, huh?
好吧，有些笑话还挺好笑的，对吧？
I don't think the crowd really enjoyed them all that much.
我觉得观众并没有那么喜欢它们。
Okay, well, maybe I'm just a fan of really terrible jokes.
好吧，也许我只是特别喜欢特别烂的笑话。
Well, they were pretty funny, but I guess the crowd just didn't appreciate his sense
嗯，它们还挺好笑的，但我猜观众就是不欣赏他的幽默感。
of humor.
他的幽默感。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
They did use quite a lot of really interesting language.
他们确实用了很多非常有趣的语言。
So why don't we look at that now in Language Takeaway.
所以我们不如现在在“语言要点”里看看这些。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
On Language Takeaway, we're going to be looking at six words today, so let's get started.
在“语言要点”里，我们今天要看六个词，所以让我们开始吧。
The announcer welcomed everyone and said that it's open mic night.
主持人欢迎大家，并说这是开放麦之夜。
Open mic night.
开放麦之夜。
So, an open mic night.
所以，开放麦之夜。
Okay, well, we know mic is short for microphone, right?
好吧，我们知道“mic”是“microphone”（麦克风）的缩写，对吧？
Now, an open mic night is a chance where anyone can come up and talk into the microphone.
现在，开放麦之夜是一个机会，任何人都可以上来对着麦克风说话。
So you can come up and sing or you can tell jokes, you can do anything, basically.
所以你可以上来唱歌，或者讲笑话，基本上什么都可以做。
Yeah.
是的。
Alright, open mic night.
好的，开放麦之夜。
So it's not for professionals, but for people who maybe want to be professionals.
所以它不是为专业人士准备的，而是为那些可能想成为专业人士的人准备的。
Right, amateurs.
对，业余爱好者。
So it was open mic night and he said they had a lot of great comics there.
所以那是开放麦之夜，他说他们那里有很多很棒的喜剧演员。
So comics.
所以是“comics”（喜剧演员）。
A comic.
一个喜剧演员。
So basically, a comic is a person that makes a living by making people laugh.
所以基本上，喜剧演员是靠逗人笑谋生的人。
Yeah, someone who stands up on stage and tells jokes.
是的，就是站在舞台上讲笑话的人。
Alright.
好的。
So, a clown is kind of like a comic?
那么，小丑有点像喜剧演员吗？
No, they're different.
不，他们不一样。
They're different, right?
他们不一样，对吧？
A comic doesn't wear a red nose and a crazy...
喜剧演员不戴红鼻子和疯狂的……
A costume.
服装。
Yeah.
是的。
Alright, yeah, because I hate clowns.
好的，是的，因为我讨厌小丑。
We do know that about you.
我们确实知道你这点。
Alright, so a comic.
好的，所以是喜剧演员。
And well, what comics do is they perform stand-up comedy.
嗯，喜剧演员做的就是表演单口喜剧。
Stand-up comedy.
单口喜剧。
Okay, so stand-up comedy is really exactly what its name suggests, right?
好的，所以单口喜剧真的就像它的名字所暗示的那样，对吧？
Right, you stand up in front of an audience and you tell jokes or you make them laugh.
对，你站在观众面前，讲笑话或逗他们笑。
Yeah, tell funny stories.
是的，讲有趣的故事。
It's a very popular form of entertainment in the United States and the UK.
在美国和英国，这是一种非常流行的娱乐形式。
That's right.
没错。
And I think we'll talk a little bit more about that at the end of the lesson, but why don't
我想我们会在课程结束时再多聊一点，但不如我们继续看下一个词，那就是“routine”（段子）。
we move on to our next word, which is routine.
一个段子。
A routine.
So the guy says, I've been working on my routine.
所以那个人说：“我一直在练习我的段子。”
So what does he mean by his routine?
那么他说的“段子”是什么意思？
Well, I guess a routine is like a series or a collection of jokes or maybe movements that
嗯，我想段子就像是一系列或一组笑话，或者你在表演中使用的动作。
you use in a performance.
好的，段子。
Alright, a routine.
所以你可以说舞蹈段子。
So you can talk about a dance routine.
或者在这种情况下，喜剧段子。
Or in this case, a comedy routine.
所以是他要讲的一系列笑话。
So the series of jokes he's going to tell.
没错，他一遍又一遍练习的那些。
That's right, that he practices again and again and again.
好的，在他的段子里，他说他有很多“zingers”（爆笑梗）。
Alright, and in his routine, he said he's got a lot of zingers.
爆笑梗。
Zingers.
一个爆笑梗。
A zinger.
那么什么是爆笑梗？
So what's a zinger?
基本上，爆笑梗就是一个强烈的、可能有点粗鲁的笑话。
Basically, a zinger is like a strong, maybe a little bit rude joke.
是的，但有点像那种一句话的笑话，对吧？
Yeah, but like a kind of a one-line joke, right?
对，没错。
Right, exactly.
And the people that were in the crowd and they were booing him, they were like, boo,
而那些在观众里对他喝倒彩的人，他们就像“嘘”，我们称他们为“hecklers”（捣乱者）。
those we call hecklers.
完全正确。
Exactly.
那是我们的最后一个词，捣乱者。
And that's our last word, a heckler.
一个捣乱者。
A heckler.
捣乱者。
Hecklers.
So, let's listen to some hecklers in action.
那么，让我们听听捣乱者实际是怎么做的。
Alright well, I think that's pretty clear.
好吧，我想这已经很清楚了。
Those are definitely hecklers.
那些绝对是捣乱者。
Right, they're very annoying.
对，他们非常烦人。
So now that we've finished looking at all the words that are related to comedy and performances,
现在我们已经看完了所有与喜剧和表演相关的词，让我们在“流利度构建”里看看这些笑话。
let's take a look at the jokes now in Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Fluency Builder.
Okay, well we're not really focusing on new phrases for you here, but we thought it would
好的，我们这里并不是要重点讲新短语，但我们觉得聊一聊这些笑话来帮助你理解会很有帮助，对吧？
be helpful to talk a little bit about the jokes to help you understand them, right?
因为它们，嗯，我觉得还挺好笑的。
Because they are, well, I think pretty funny.
是的，它们挺好笑的，但有时可能有点难懂。
Yeah, they're pretty funny, but maybe sometimes they're kind of hard to understand.
所以不如我们从第一个笑话开始？
So why don't we start with the first joke?
所以你说：“你在哪里能找到一条腿的狗？”
So you said, where do you find a one-legged dog?
那么什么是“一条腿的狗”？
So what's a one-legged dog?
基本上，就是只有一条腿的狗。
Basically, it's a dog that has one leg.
啊，好的，这里的发音很重要，对吧？
Ah, okay, and the pronunciation here is important, right?
一条腿的。
One-legged.
不。
No.
一条腿的。
One-legged.
所以你可以说一条腿的狗、两条腿的狗或三条腿的狗。
So you can say a one-legged dog, a two-legged dog, or a three-legged dog.
Six-legged dog?
六条腿的狗？
A six-legged spider.
一只六条腿的蜘蛛。
Maybe he lost two legs in a war.
也许它在战争中丢了两条腿。
Oh dear.
哦，天哪。
Okay, so the dog obviously didn't go anywhere, and so that's why you find it where you left
好吧，所以狗显然哪儿也没去，这就是为什么你在离开的地方找到它
it.
它。
Exactly.
没错。
So that's why it's kind of funny.
所以这就是它有点好笑的原因。
Okay.
好吧。
All right, so then he said, what do you call a sheep with no legs?
好了，然后他说，没有腿的羊叫什么？
I don't know.
我不知道。
A cloud, basically, because sheep are fluffy and they're white, so if you take away their
基本上叫一朵云，因为羊毛茸茸的、白色的，所以如果你去掉它们的
legs, they look like a little cloud.
腿，它们看起来就像一朵小云。
Boo!
嘘！
All right, let's look at the next one.
好了，我们来看下一个。
He asked, what do cows do for entertainment?
他问，牛为了娱乐做什么？
And then the answer was, they rent movies.
然后答案是，它们租电影看。
Exactly.
没错。
So it's kind of funny because he's relating this word movies with the sound that cows
所以这有点好笑，因为他把“电影”这个词和牛发出的
make, which is moo.
声音“哞”联系起来了。
Right.
对。
So there are a million jokes in English following the same pattern, right?
所以英语里有无数个遵循同样模式的笑话，对吧？
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
So I'm sure you can find a lot more of them and you can share them with us.
所以我肯定你能找到更多，你可以和我们分享。
Now my personal favorite joke is, the guy says, what does a fish say when it runs into
现在我个人最喜欢的笑话是，那人说，鱼撞到墙上时会说什么？
a wall?
墙？
So to run into a wall, basically, to crash against the wall.
所以“撞到墙”基本上就是撞到墙上。
Yep.
嗯。
So what does the fish say?
那鱼说什么？
Damn.
该死。
So why is this funny?
为什么这好笑？
Why does he say damn?
为什么它说“该死”？
Well, because, I mean, if you're a person and you run into a wall, damn, like, you know,
嗯，因为，我的意思是，如果你是一个人撞到墙上，你会说“该死”，就像，
it's like, oh no.
哦不。
Yeah.
是的。
But a fish is swimming under the water and like we saw, a dam is actually like a wall
但鱼在水里游，就像我们看到的，水坝实际上就像水里的
in the water.
一堵墙。
So he's saying like, a wall.
所以它说的是，一堵墙。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
对对对。
So I like that one.
所以我喜欢那个。
All right.
好了。
The last one was pretty good.
最后一个挺不错的。
Why do gorillas have big nostrils?
为什么大猩猩有大鼻孔？
Okay, so the big holes in their nose.
好吧，就是它们鼻子上的大洞。
Right.
对。
And basically, it's because they have big fingers.
基本上，因为它们有大手指。
So they can put their fingers in the nose?
所以它们可以把手指放进鼻子里？
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
Oh dear.
哦，天哪。
If he didn't have big nostrils, he wouldn't be able to pick his nose.
如果它没有大鼻孔，它就没法挖鼻子了。
Maybe he'd have to use a stick.
也许它得用根棍子。
Yeah, but that wouldn't be convenient.
是啊，但那不方便。
See?
看到了吧？
All right.
好了。
So that's why those jokes are funny.
所以这就是那些笑话好笑的原因。
They're very short jokes.
它们是非常短的笑话。
Of course, some of them are not actually really funny, but it's just a little bit of a taste
当然，有些其实并不好笑，但这只是让你尝尝
of short American jokes.
美国短笑话的味道。
Okay, well, I think we need to hear them one more time in context so you can all know how
好吧，我觉得我们需要在上下文中再听一遍，这样你们就能知道它们
funny or maybe not so funny they are.
有多好笑，或者也许没那么好笑。
Hello everyone and welcome to Open Mic Night.
大家好，欢迎来到开放麦克风之夜。
You're in for a real treat as we've got a lot of great comics here with us tonight.
你们今晚有福了，因为我们这里有很多很棒的喜剧演员。
First up, we have a very funny man coming straight from the state of Montana, Robert
首先，我们有一位非常有趣的男士，他直接从蒙大拿州来，罗伯特
Hicks.
希克斯。
Thank you, everyone.
谢谢大家。
Well, what a lovely crowd.
哇，多可爱的观众啊。
You know, there's nothing I love better than stand-up comedy.
你知道，我最喜欢的就是单口喜剧了。
You know, I've been working on my routine for months now and I've got some real zingers
你知道，我几个月来一直在准备我的段子，今晚我给你们准备了一些真正的
for you tonight.
妙语。
Let's start out with some short jokes.
我们先从一些短笑话开始。
How about that?
怎么样？
Where do you find a one-legged dog?
你在哪里能找到一条腿的狗？
Where you left it.
你离开它的地方。
Get it?
明白了吗？
Anyways, what do you call a sheep with no legs?
不管怎样，没有腿的羊叫什么？
A cloud.
一朵云。
Tough crowd.
难搞的观众。
All right, now you're going to love this joke.
好了，现在你们会喜欢这个笑话的。
It's hilarious.
它超好笑。
What do cows do for entertainment?
牛为了娱乐做什么？
They rent movies.
它们租电影看。
Movies.
电影。
Okay, okay, okay.
好吧，好吧，好吧。
We've got a few hecklers in the audience, but this one is good.
观众里有几个捣乱的，但这个笑话不错。
What does a fish say when it runs into a wall?
鱼撞到墙上时会说什么？
Damn!
该死！
Get out of here.
滚出去。
Okay, okay, okay.
好吧，好吧，好吧。
Last one.
最后一个。
Why do gorillas have big nostrils?
为什么大猩猩有大鼻孔？
Because they got big fingers.
因为它们有大手指。
Thanks everyone, that was my time.
谢谢大家，我的时间到了。
Now if you have any good jokes of your own, why don't you come to our website and tell
如果你们自己有什么好笑话，为什么不来我们的网站告诉我们呢？
us about them.
告诉我们。
Right, come to EnglishPod.com, share with us any jokes.
对，来EnglishPod.com，和我们分享任何笑话。
Of course, they have to be clean.
当然，它们得是干净的。
Don't come with any...
别带任何...
No, yeah, no swears.
不，是的，不许骂人。
No swearing in the jokes.
笑话里不许骂人。
Yep.
嗯。
All right, so we'll see you guys there and until next time.
好了，那我们就在那里见你们，下次再见。
Thanks for listening and goodbye.
感谢收听，再见。
Bye.
再见。